[
  {
    "question": "Alfred Kroeber spent his career teaching at",
    "a": "Princeton",
    "b": "Harvard",
    "c": "Columbia",
    "d": "Stanford",
    "e": "the University of California, Berkeley",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ishi is the Yahi word for",
    "a": "\"one\"",
    "b": "\"love\"",
    "c": "\"man\"",
    "d": "\"human\"",
    "e": "\"alone\"",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Alfred Kroeber took custody of Ishi, he sent Ishi to",
    "a": "tour the country and speak",
    "b": "live with a nearby Indian tribe",
    "c": "conduct research at a lab",
    "d": "perform at his museum",
    "e": "learn American culture",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "After retiring from teaching, Alfred Kroeber",
    "a": "reconsidered his time with Ishi",
    "b": "gave lectures on the Yahi tribe",
    "c": "wrote biographies on Ishi",
    "d": "tried to restore the Yahi homeland",
    "e": "published his research on the Yahi tribe",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following architects designed Semper Virens?",
    "a": "Bernard Maybeck",
    "b": "Greg Castillo",
    "c": "Sabrina Richards",
    "d": "David K. Burton",
    "e": "Frederick Law Olmstead",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following properties became the setting for the novel Always Coming Home?",
    "a": "a Victorian home in Northwest Portland",
    "b": "a ranch in Napa Valley",
    "c": "an apartment in Massachusetts",
    "d": "a home in the Berkeley hills",
    "e": "a beach cottage in Oregon",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin modeled Shvek, the Anarresti physicist in the novel The Dispossessed, after",
    "a": "James B. Conant",
    "b": "Enrico Fermi",
    "c": "J. Robert Oppenheimer",
    "d": "Ernest O. Lawrence",
    "e": "Crawford Greenewalt",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin attended high school with fellow science fiction author",
    "a": "J.G. Ballard",
    "b": "Roger Zelazny",
    "c": "Frank Herbert",
    "d": "Kurt Vonnegut",
    "e": "Philip K. Dick",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin met her husband while studying in",
    "a": "Germany",
    "b": "Spain",
    "c": "Italy",
    "d": "Britain",
    "e": "France",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "The Le Guins often explored the martial art of",
    "a": "taekwondo",
    "b": "tai chi",
    "c": "jiu-jitsu",
    "d": "aikido",
    "e": "judo",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin struggled early on as a writer when editors",
    "a": "wanted her to be more conservative",
    "b": "didn't believe she had talent",
    "c": "delayed her publications",
    "d": "could not market her books",
    "e": "considered her narratives too outlandish",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin wrote all of the following novels in her early career EXCEPT",
    "a": "Rocannon's World",
    "b": "City of Illusions",
    "c": "Lavinia",
    "d": "Planet of Exile",
    "e": "A Wizard of Earthsea",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin's The Left Hand of Darkness speculates about",
    "a": "race",
    "b": "human rights",
    "c": "gender",
    "d": "freedom",
    "e": "sexuality",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following novels by Ursula K. Le Guin became a Newberry Honor?",
    "a": "Always Coming Home",
    "b": "The Farthest Shore",
    "c": "The Dispossessed",
    "d": "The Tombs of Atuan",
    "e": "The Lathe of Heaven",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin spent much of her last years",
    "a": "riding horses",
    "b": "meeting with a novel group",
    "c": "traveling Europe",
    "d": "gardening",
    "e": "blogging",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following events did NOT influence Ursula K. Le Guin’s career?",
    "a": "the Holocaust",
    "b": "World War Two",
    "c": "World War I",
    "d": "the Vietnam War",
    "e": "the fall of the Soviet Union",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following actions inspired Ursula K. Le Guin’s The Left Hand of Darkness?",
    "a": "pulling an ice sledge",
    "b": "climbing the steps of a temple",
    "c": "watching a storm through a window",
    "d": "shaping a pot from clay",
    "e": "skipping stones on a pond",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin's The Left Hand of Darkness PRIMARILY reflects the ideas of",
    "a": "the Civil Rights movement",
    "b": "the anti-Vietnam War movement",
    "c": "First Wave Feminism",
    "d": "environmentalism",
    "e": "Second Wave Feminism",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following novels gives voice to an originally mute female character?",
    "a": "Lavinia",
    "b": "The Tombs of Atuan",
    "c": "Tehanu",
    "d": "The Other Wind",
    "e": "The Farthest Shore",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following authors published under the pseudonym James Tiptree, Jr.?",
    "a": "Kate Wilhelm",
    "b": "Alice Sheldon",
    "c": "Eileen Gunn",
    "d": "Melissa Scott",
    "e": "Elizabeth Lynn",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following authors joined the field of science fiction during the Second American Women’s Movement EXCEPT",
    "a": "Vonda N. McIntyre",
    "b": "Joanna Russ",
    "c": "Marge Piercy",
    "d": "Lauren Beukes",
    "e": "Margaret Atwood",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin’s The Word for World is Forest depicts the devastation wrought by the use of",
    "a": "Napalm",
    "b": "Agent Orange",
    "c": "fighter aircraft",
    "d": "atomic weapons",
    "e": "Machine Guns",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following novels addresses past and ongoing human rights violations?",
    "a": "Always Coming Home",
    "b": "The Dispossessed",
    "c": "Rocannon’s World",
    "d": "The Telling",
    "e": "The Word for World is Forest",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin’s The Dispossessed provides a meditation on the",
    "a": "Civil Rights movement",
    "b": "bombing of Hiroshima and Nagasaki",
    "c": "Energy crisis",
    "d": "Cold War",
    "e": "AIDs crisis",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Ursula K. Le Guin, which of the following Taoist ideas influenced The Lathe of Heaven?",
    "a": "“integrity”",
    "b": "“harmony”",
    "c": "“compassion”",
    "d": "“vitality”",
    "e": "“patience”",
    "correct_answer": "a"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ursula K. Le Guin’s The Lathe of Heaven presents commentary on all of the following issues EXCEPT",
    "a": "shrinking natural resources",
    "b": "climate change",
    "c": "gender inequality",
    "d": "overpopulation",
    "e": "pollution",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kwashiorkor results from a lack of",
    "a": "ions",
    "b": "fat",
    "c": "white blood cells",
    "d": "protein",
    "e": "glycogen",
    "correct_answer": "d"
  },
  {
    "question": "Doctors in The Lathe of Heaven disguise cases of kwashiorkor as",
    "a": "typhus",
    "b": "tuberculosis",
    "c": "scurvy",
    "d": "cholera",
    "e": "influenza",
    "correct_answer": "c"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following fictional societies appears in Ursula K. Le Guin’s Always Coming Home?",
    "a": "the Hainish",
    "b": "the Shing",
    "c": "the Gethenians",
    "d": "the Ekumen",
    "e": "the Kesh",
    "correct_answer": "e"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following issues appears MOST in Ursula K. Le Guin’s Always Coming Home?",
    "a": "gender inequality",
    "b": "shrinking natural resources",
    "c": "terrorism",
    "d": "world hunger",
    "e": "global warming",
    "correct_answer": "b"
  }
]

